<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Brettrics</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Brettrics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 21:20:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantified Self – Analysis of my Time</title>
      <link>/quant-self-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 21:20:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/quant-self-time/</guid>
      <description>Almost every day I am looking at data either for my job or personal development. A lot of the time I am looking at data that is describing something like TSA claims or the metallurgy of bicycles. As an analyst, I am always trying to synthesize stories from data to help bring insight to my team. Now I am starting to look at my habits and figure out how I can synthesize stories about myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steel is Not So Real Anymore – Analysis of 25 Years of Bicycles</title>
      <link>/bicycles-through-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 06:42:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bicycles-through-time/</guid>
      <description>As an avid cyclist and bicycle mechanic, I have always taken a keen interest in how bicycles have evolved with technology. From the original modified “klunker” mountain bikes to the carbon fiber electronic shifting road bikes, bikes have come a long way and will continue to advance. We can look at this change in technology and start to see the shifts in the industry by observing the historical archives.
Let explore some of the long-debated questions that keep popping up on bicycle message boards and talked about on those weekend rides with your dentist on his $6000 Pinarello.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of TSA Claims – Less than Expected</title>
      <link>/tsa-claims/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 18:32:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tsa-claims/</guid>
      <description>As I continue on my journey as an analyst, I keep running across interesting datasets. Over the last few weeks, I have been interested in various datasets around flying. So far I have found TSA claims from the past fifteen years and the number of passengers that have flown in the United States. Starting with the TSA claims, I wanted to see if I could find anything interesting.
First I wanted to acknowledge that it was a bit of challenge to collect and clean this data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What 9 Million Parking Tickets Says About Los Angeles</title>
      <link>/9-million-parking-tickets-la/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 06:58:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/9-million-parking-tickets-la/</guid>
      <description>Over the last 4 years the Los Angeles Department of Transportation has given out 655 million dollars worth of parking tickets. As a resident of Southern California, I am all too familiar with walking out to my car after running inside real quick to grab my hat and finding that dreaded sun-faded white and yellow carbon paper on my windshield. All over Los Angeles, this is happening at an astonishing rate, on average 7000 cars are being written up every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Years of Color – Analysis on my Personal Photo Collection</title>
      <link>/10-years-of-color/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 23:44:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/10-years-of-color/</guid>
      <description>Following a similar trend to the analysis of Van Gogh’s painting I did, I wanted to explore my own personal photo history. Photography has been such a large part of my life the last 10 years, in fact I have managed to take about 15,000 photos. I would have never guessed I was taking so many photos. Photos can show so much about your life, and it is so strange to think that I pretty much have my life well-documented since middle school, well at least well documented with a digital camera.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>