<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brettrics</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Brettrics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Theortical - Using Time on Page for Recommendation Engine</title>
      <link>/theortical-using-time-on-page-for-recommendation-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/theortical-using-time-on-page-for-recommendation-engine/</guid>
      <description>Resources: https://blog.parse.ly/post/3677/reco-2/ Youtube</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Sparklines for Blog Post with R and Plumber</title>
      <link>/creating-sparklines-for-blog-post-with-r-and-plumber/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/creating-sparklines-for-blog-post-with-r-and-plumber/</guid>
      <description>One of my favorite R libraries is the plumber, having the abibilty to quickly turn any of my R code into an API allows for anyone use my functions or data. Wanting to explore some use cases in the digital analytics relm for. One thing I have always been interested in was when a blog would show a trendline or spark line of an article. It is nice to see an organization being a transparent with some of the data they are collecting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Journey Across the US</title>
      <link>/my-journey-across-the-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/my-journey-across-the-us/</guid>
      <description>Recent I moved across the United States with my wife and dog. Previously I lived in Pasadena, CA and now I am in South Bend, IN. After doing alot of packing and coordinatoring large cubes shippments we were off from California to Indiana. I was wanting to do something with data and collection for the drive across. So in my phone I set up a Tasker app to record a file of alot of different variables that phones collect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What gutting Net Neutrality is worth?</title>
      <link>/net-neutrality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 23:57:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/net-neutrality/</guid>
      <description>This is built from a simple web scrapper using R. It shows different aspects of which states sold out when it came to net neutrality.
Data from https://www.theverge.com/2017/3/29/15100620/congress-fcc-isp-web-browsing-privacy-fire-sale</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where can you buy an Adventure Pass in Southern California?</title>
      <link>/map-adventure-pass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 01:12:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/map-adventure-pass/</guid>
      <description>Recently I went camping in Los Angeles and found it difficult to plan all the coordination, especially dealing with the purchasing of an Adventure Pass. Currently this is the website that provides a list of where you can purchase one. Well, I was not too impressed with just a list of vendors that I had to search and sift through. So I built a quick web scraper, geocoded each of the address and plotted them on an interactive map.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantified Self – Analysis of my Time</title>
      <link>/quant-self-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 21:20:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/quant-self-time/</guid>
      <description>Almost every day I am looking at data either for my job or personal development. A lot of the time I am looking at data that is describing something like TSA claims or the metallurgy of bicycles. As an analyst, I am always trying to synthesize stories from data to help bring insight to my team. Now I am starting to look at my habits and figure out how I can synthesize stories about myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Few Helpful R Packages</title>
      <link>/a-few-helpful-r-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 05:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/a-few-helpful-r-packages/</guid>
      <description>There are a few packages in R that I wish I was exposed to earlier, if I had an understanding of these packages earlier I would have been on Stack Overflow less. These are some of the most common packages that I use.
 tidyverse #hadlyverse dplyr #grouping tidyr #reshaping ggplot2 #plotting magrittr #pipefowarding lubridate #dates stringr #strings tidytext #moreStrings This list will continue to grow as I think of more packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steel is Not So Real Anymore – Analysis of 25 Years of Bicycles</title>
      <link>/bicycles-through-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 06:42:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bicycles-through-time/</guid>
      <description>As an avid cyclist and bicycle mechanic, I have always taken a keen interest in how bicycles have evolved with technology. From the original modified “klunker” mountain bikes to the carbon fiber electronic shifting road bikes, bikes have come a long way and will continue to advance. We can look at this change in technology and start to see the shifts in the industry by observing the historical archives.
Let explore some of the long-debated questions that keep popping up on bicycle message boards and talked about on those weekend rides with your dentist on his $6000 Pinarello.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of TSA Claims – Less than Expected</title>
      <link>/tsa-claims/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 18:32:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tsa-claims/</guid>
      <description>As I continue on my journey as an analyst, I keep running across interesting datasets. Over the last few weeks, I have been interested in various datasets around flying. So far I have found TSA claims from the past fifteen years and the number of passengers that have flown in the United States. Starting with the TSA claims, I wanted to see if I could find anything interesting.
First I wanted to acknowledge that it was a bit of challenge to collect and clean this data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Driving Sucks on Thursdays – Analysis of my Commute</title>
      <link>/driving-sucks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 04:24:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/driving-sucks/</guid>
      <description>YA. I have been commuting through downtown LA for the last 6 months and have noticed some strange phenomenon over the weeks. Consistently I have found some days worse than others. Google Maps is one of my favorite applications and if I had to give up every app but one, I would save Google Maps. This application has allowed for me to explore all over Los Angeles and is the reason I was able to safely navigate the California coast on my bike tour several summers ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What 9 Million Parking Tickets Says About Los Angeles</title>
      <link>/9-million-parking-tickets-la/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 06:58:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/9-million-parking-tickets-la/</guid>
      <description>Over the last 4 years the Los Angeles Department of Transportation has given out 655 million dollars worth of parking tickets. As a resident of Southern California, I am all too familiar with walking out to my car after running inside real quick to grab my hat and finding that dreaded sun-faded white and yellow carbon paper on my windshield. All over Los Angeles, this is happening at an astonishing rate, on average 7000 cars are being written up every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Years of Color – Analysis on my Personal Photo Collection</title>
      <link>/10-years-of-color/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 23:44:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/10-years-of-color/</guid>
      <description>Following a similar trend to the analysis of Van Gogh’s painting I did, I wanted to explore my own personal photo history. Photography has been such a large part of my life the last 10 years, in fact I have managed to take about 15,000 photos. I would have never guessed I was taking so many photos. Photos can show so much about your life, and it is so strange to think that I pretty much have my life well-documented since middle school, well at least well documented with a digital camera.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to “Hack” Psychology Internships</title>
      <link>/psychology-internship/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 19:05:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/psychology-internship/</guid>
      <description>This project started because my wife will eventually need to find an internship in order to graduate from grad school. As she told me more about the process, it sounded like a headache. There are more psych students than there are psych internships. Knowing this I wanted to give her as much of a competitive edge as I could. So instead of relying on APPIC and her school to help her find one, I decided to use my knowledge to help figure it out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pixel Implementation QA with Google Speadsheets</title>
      <link>/pixel-implementation-google-spreadsheets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 07:13:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pixel-implementation-google-spreadsheets/</guid>
      <description>We all know pixel implementations range from being simple such as putting an image tag on a page to a complex function that dynamically takes apart your order and creates individual pixels for each of the items in your cart. Whether you are just a simple pixel pusher or an actual developer who works with tag management systems, you might find this tutorial helpful.
Google Tag Manager is a great system to help create pixels because it allows for data to be easily appended onto the pixel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Van Gogh’s Life through his Favorite Colors</title>
      <link>/vincent_van_gogh_color/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 03:12:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/vincent_van_gogh_color/</guid>
      <description>I set out to understand the life of a man through the colors he chose to use. Vincent van Gogh was an amazing painter who changed the art world more then he will ever know.
 What would life be if we had no courage to attempt anything? – Vincent van Gogh
 As Vincent declared I wanted to have the courage to keep exploring data and discover the meaning behind it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This American Life – Visualized pt. 2</title>
      <link>/tal-speaking-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2016 18:55:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tal-speaking-rate/</guid>
      <description>Over the years we can start to see the average speaking rate of This American Life increase!
  var divElement = document.getElementById(&#39;1&#39;); var vizElement = divElement.getElementsByTagName(&#39;object&#39;)[0]; vizElement.style.width=&#39;100%&#39;; vizElement.style.height=&#39;900px&#39;; var scriptElement = document.createElement(&#39;script&#39;); scriptElement.src = &#39;https://public.tableau.com/javascripts/api/viz_v1.js&#39;; vizElement.parentNode.insertBefore(scriptElement, vizElement);  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How often was Michelle Dugger pregnant?</title>
      <link>/dugger-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2016 06:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dugger-data/</guid>
      <description>Over the last 20 years Michelle Dugger, of recently cancelled TLC series 19 Kids and Counting, has been pregnant 17 times! On average she become pregnant only after 8 months of each child being born.
  var divElement = document.getElementById(&#39;viz1532446909538&#39;); var vizElement = divElement.getElementsByTagName(&#39;object&#39;)[0]; vizElement.style.width=&#39;100%&#39;; vizElement.style.height=&#39;900px&#39;; var scriptElement = document.createElement(&#39;script&#39;); scriptElement.src = &#39;https://public.tableau.com/javascripts/api/viz_v1.js&#39;; vizElement.parentNode.insertBefore(scriptElement, vizElement);  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stray dogs in Los Angeles, CA</title>
      <link>/stary_dogs_in_la/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 17:19:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/stary_dogs_in_la/</guid>
      <description> Every day stray dogs are picked up and brought in to animal shelters in Los Angeles, CA. Who are these dogs? How many of them were abandoned? Below is a data visualization with data from the Los Angeles Data Portal.
   var divElement = document.getElementById(&#39;viz1532442378946&#39;); var vizElement = divElement.getElementsByTagName(&#39;object&#39;)[0]; vizElement.style.width=&#39;100%&#39;; vizElement.style.height=&#39;900px&#39;; var scriptElement = document.createElement(&#39;script&#39;); scriptElement.src = &#39;https://public.tableau.com/javascripts/api/viz_v1.js&#39;; vizElement.parentNode.insertBefore(scriptElement, vizElement);  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This American Life – Visualized</title>
      <link>/this-american-life-visualized/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 15:50:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/this-american-life-visualized/</guid>
      <description>This American Life does an amazing job at telling stories about everyday people. As an avid listener I have come to love the journeys that Ira Glass &amp;amp; his producers are able to take me through. I have been using TAL’s website for the last several years and I wanted to try and provide a new way to interact with it. Below is two ways that provides a new way to interact and listen to the podcast of This American Life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page Engagement: A New Measure of Success</title>
      <link>/page-engagement-a-new-measure-of-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 04:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page-engagement-a-new-measure-of-success/</guid>
      <description>One of the biggest questions in web analytics right now is “How do we know users are reading or looking at our content?” In the past, Liferay has used “page views” and “number of clicks” to determine the popularity of our content, but we’re now learning that these methods do not necessarily determine the success of a page. Page views show how users are navigating through your site, but they will not provide the strongest insight about what they are truly interested in.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>